// flashcards/navigation.js
export const navigation = [
      { front : `What is a tango route?`, back: `A low-altitude RNAV airway` },
      { front : `Which type of NAVAID has a 2-digit identifier?`, back: `NDB: Non-Directional Beacon` },
      { front : `What is MOCA, and what does it guarantee?`, back: `Minimum Obstacle Clearance Altitude is the minimum altitude at which an aircraft canfly, while maintaining acceptable clearance above ground-based obstacles` },
      { front : `What does the Global Positioning System consist of?`, back: `Orbiting satellites` },
      { front : `What is "course"?`, back: `The direction the aircraft is actually traveling over the ground, regardless of its heading` },
      { front : `What is a compass locator (LOM)?`, back: `An NDB co-located with a marker beacon (often an outer marker)` },
      { front : `What is slant range?`, back: `The distance measured directly through the air from the aircraft to the NAVAID (in other words, not the distance along the ground)` },
      { front : `What is a Q-route?`, back: `A high-altitude RNAV airway` },
      { front : `What are the componets of an Instrument Landing System?`, back: "<ul><li>Glideslope (vertical guidance)</li><li>Localizer (horizontal/lateral guidance)</li><li>Approach Lighting System (visual guidance)</li><li>Marker Beacons (range/distance information)</li></ul>" },
      { front : `Which 2 types of NAVAIDs have 5-digit identifiers?`, back: `Fixes and waypoints` },
      { front : `Which type of NAVAID has a 4-digit identifier, beginning with the letter "I"?`, back: `Localizer` },
      { front : `What is a fix/waypoint?`, back: `A point in space, deemed important for navigation` },
      { front : `What latitude is considered to be south polar?`, back: `60°S` },
      { front : `What is a visual descent point (VDP)?`, back: `The point after which a pilot is permitted to descend below his or her MDA, if they have the runway in sight` },
      { front : `What is DME?`, back: `Distance Measuring Equipment measures the slant range distance, in nautical miles, between itself and an aircraft` },
      { front : `What is a victor route?`, back: `A low-altitude airway connecting VORs` },
      { front : `Do fixes and waypoints signify the presence of physical objects, facilities, etc?`, back: `No, they're just points in space` },
      { front : `What is an air route that's built on NDBs called?`, back: `Colored route` },
      { front : `What is meant by "service volume," in relation to a VOR?`, back: `The range, in nautical miles, that the VOR's signal is guaranteed to be broadcast` },
      { front : `What does the Automatic Direction Finder (ADF) do?`, back: `ADFs provide a relative bearing to the selected NDB` },
      { front : `What latitude is considered to be north polar?`, back: `78°N` },
      { front : `How many satellites are required for the Global Positioning System to locate an aircraft in the air?`, back: `4` },
      { front : `What is the range of a high service volume VOR?`, back: `130 NM` },
      { front : `What are some locations where waypoints can be found?`, back: "<ul><li>At the intersection of radials from 2 VORs</li><li>At the intersection of a radial and a localizer</li><li>At the intersection of any 2 points of longitude and latitude</li></ul>" },
      { front : `To which non-RNAV approach type is an LNAV approach similar?`, back: `Localizer (LOC)` },
      { front : `What is the range of a terminal service volume VOR?`, back: `25 NM` },
      { front : `What does the Radio Magnetic Indicator (RMI) do?`, back: `The RMI interprets and displays input from the Automatic Direction Finder (ADF)` },
      { front : `What is a VORTAC?`, back: `A VOR that is co-lated with a military TACAN` },
      { front : `What is an NDB?`, back: `A Non-directional Beacon is a NAVAID that provides range information, via the aircraft's Automatic Direction Finder` },
      { front : `How many satellites are required for the Global Positioning System to locate an aircraft on the ground?`, back: `3` },
      { front : `What is a STAR?`, back: `A Standard Terminal Arrival Route (or Standard Arrival) procedure` },
      { front : `What does RNAV provide, and how does it work?`, back: `Area Navigation allows for direct flight between any two sets of coordinates, using a combination of data compiled by individual GPS, DME, INS, and/or VOR sources, which is used to plot and display the aircraft's present position on the EFIS` },
      { front : `What is MORA, and what does it guarantee?`, back: `Minimum Off-Route Altitude is the minimum altitude at which an aircraft can fly, while not on a victor route or jet route, and still be guaranteed minimum obstacle clerance (MOCA)` },
      { front : `What is the range of a low service volume VOR?`, back: `40 NM` },
      { front : `What is an MEA gap?`, back: `An area within which an aircraft may lose NAVAID reception, even when flying at or above the Minimum Enroute Altitude` },
      { front : `What is WAAS?`, back: `A type of RAIM, a Wide Area Augmentation System is a ground-based GPS "satellite," employed to improve the accuracy of GPS data` },
      { front : `What is a jet route?`, back: `A high-altitude airway connecting VORs` },
      { front : `What is a SID?`, back: `A Standard Instrument Departure procedure` },
      { front : `What is MEA, and what does it guarantee?`, back: `Minimum Enroute Altitude is the minimum altitude at which an aircraft can fly, while being guaranteed both obstacle clearance and NAVAID reception` },
      { front : `What are some locations where fixes can be found?`, back: "<ul><li>At the intersection of radials from 2 VORs</li><li>At the intersection of a radial and a localizer</li></ul>" },
      { front : `What does flying at or below MAA help to prevent?`, back: `NAVAID interference` },
      { front : `What is a VOR?`, back: `An aviation NAVAID that serves as the basis for a low- and high-altitude air routes` },
      { front : `What is the purpose of RAIM?`, back: `Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring helps to ensure the accuracy of satellite-based navigational information, by cross-checking it against other sources` },
      { front : `What is OROCA?`, back: `Off-Route Obstruction Clearance Altitude is another name for MORA` },
      { front : `How does a VOR determine an aircraft's position?`, back: `Radials` },
      { front : `How much vertical clearance does MOCA provide over non-mountainous terrain?`, back: `1000'` },
      { front : `To which non-RNAV approach type is an LNAV/VANV approach similar?`, back: `ILS` },
      { front : `What is a "heading"?`, back: `The direction the aircraft's nose is pointing` },
      { front : `Can you plan to use an RNAV approach?`, back: `Yes, for the destination or alternate, but not for both` },
      { front : `Which typeo f NAVAID has a 3-digit identifier?`, back: `VOR` },
      { front : `What does a VOR with DME provide to the flightcrew?`, back: `Distance from the VOR on the selected radial` },
      { front : `Why might an aircraft's heading differ from its course?`, back: `Crosswinds pushing the nose to one side or the other` },
      { front : `To which non-RNAV approach type is an LPV approach similar?`, back: `CAT I ILS` },
      { front : `Is an RNAV approach considered precision or non-precision?`, back: `Non-precision` },
      { front : `Does aviation utilize true or magnetic heading?`, back: `Magnetic` },
      { front : `How much vertical clearance does MOCA provide over mountainous terrain?`, back: `2000'` },
      { front : `What is MAA`, back: `Maximum Authorized Altitude, or the altitude above which an aircraft may encounter NAVAID interference` },
      { front : `In a word, how does the Global Positioning System determine an aircraft's position?`, back: `Triangulation` },
];
